<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>best practices on Canadian Data Guy</title>
    <link>https://canadiandataguy.com/categories/best-practices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in best practices on Canadian Data Guy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 01:04:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://canadiandataguy.com/categories/best-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spark Streaming Best Practices-A bare minimum checklist for Beginners and Advanced Users</title>
      <link>https://canadiandataguy.com/blog/2023-04-18-spark-streaming-best-practices-a-bare-minimum-checklist-for-beginners-and-advanced-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 01:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://canadiandataguy.com/blog/2023-04-18-spark-streaming-best-practices-a-bare-minimum-checklist-for-beginners-and-advanced-users/</guid>
      <description>Spark Streaming Best Practices-A bare minimum checklist for Beginners and Advanced Users Most good things in life come with a nuance. While learning Streaming a few years ago, I spent hours searching for best practices. However, I would find answers to be complicated to make sense for a beginner’s mind. Thus, I devised a set of best practices that should hold true in almost all scenarios.
The below checklist is not ordered, you should aim to check off as many items as you can.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Databricks Workspace Best Practices- A checklist for both beginners and Advanced Users</title>
      <link>https://canadiandataguy.com/blog/databricksworkspacebestpracticesachecklistforbothbeginnersandadvancedusers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 17:35:21 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://canadiandataguy.com/blog/databricksworkspacebestpracticesachecklistforbothbeginnersandadvancedusers/</guid>
      <description>Databricks Workspace Best Practices- A checklist for both beginners and Advanced Users Most good things in life come with a nuance. While learning Databricks a few years ago, I spent hours searching for best practices. Thus, I devised a set of best rules that should hold in almost all scenarios. These will help you start on the right foot.
Here are some basic rules for using Databricks Workspace: Version control everything: Use Repos and organize your notebooks and folders: Keep your notebooks and files in folders to make them easy to find and manage.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
